Guide to the Yale College Records Concerning its Internship Program
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale College records concerning its internship program
1975-1983
RU 570
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5
(12 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, reports, applications, resumes, financial records, and histories documenting the activities and operations of the Yale College internship program.
Yale College (1887- )
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 9-E (YRG 9-E), Records documenting Yale College offices, programs, and projects.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Biographical / Historical
The Yale College Internship Program began in 1975 under the directorship of A. Tappan Wilder. The program, which ran in conjunction with Yale Summer Term, placed 25 undergraduates a year in government, business, and media internships during fall or spring term. In 1979 the Yale Summer Program ended, raising questions about the future of the internship program. In the same year Wilder left Yale, and Antonia Stolper, a former intern, was appointed to replace him. Stolper left Yale in 1980. Jean Cahoon took charge of the program, and seven interns were given positions. Information was gathered concerning the p08s~bility of linking the Internship Program to Environmental Studies. In 1981 nine interns were given positions. In 1982 the program went defunct.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, reports, applications, resumes, financial records, and histories documenting the activities and operations of the Yale College internship program.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Internship programs; Yale College (1887- ); Yale University -- Funds and scholarships
- Records of the Internship Program, 1975-1983; Accession 1983-A-054
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2019.
  Scope and Contents
  No online inventory available. Paper inventory available in repository.
  The papers are divided into three sections: Office Files, Financial Records, and Student Reports: Office Files contains correspondence by the directors of the program, information on advisory committees and internships, and general information concerning the history and development of the program. Financial Records contains information concerning the disposition of the internship account, and grants offered to the program, as well as invoices and receipts. Student Reports contains the applications, and mid-year and final reports of the interns. Each section is arranged chronologically, and then alphabetically within each year.
  - Office Files
    - Draft Proposal for Internship Program (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Evaluation of Program, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - General Information Concerning Internship, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Intern Lists, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "An Internship for the MPPM Program" by Clayton P. Alderfor, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Internships: Corporate, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Internship Surveys, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Memo-Approach t.o the Alfred P. Sloan Foundation for Internship Support, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Hemo Off-Term Internships in the Private Sector for Yale Undergraduates, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Staff Resumes, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Summer Term, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Applicant Lists, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Application for Internship Program, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Committee on Teaching in Residential Colleges (Porter Committee), 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Evaluation of Program, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Faculty Internship Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Forms -blank, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - General Information on Internship Program, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Intern Lists, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Internships: Kuku Ryku Theatre Laboratory, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Internships offered, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Internship surveys, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Memos to Interns, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Public Relations, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Resumes - Former Interns, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Status Report, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Summer Term - Guest Lecturers, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - University Council, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Washington Wing of Program, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Advisory Committee, Yale College Internship Program, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Applicant Lists, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Fact Sheets and Follow-up Information on Interns, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Final Reports -Summary & Appendices, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Follow-up letters, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Forms - blank, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Future of the Internship Program, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - General Information, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Guest Speakers, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Intern Lists, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Internships Offered, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Internships offered: State Department, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Internship Surveys, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Memos to Interns, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Miscellaneous, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Nen Haven Historical Society, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - The New Haven Register: clippings, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - New York Advisory Committee: correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - New York Wing of Prograr, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Staff Resumes, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Summer Tarm, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Washington Advisory Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Washington Wing of Program, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Wilder, A. Tappan: correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Advisory Committee: Yale College Internship Program, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Faculty Mailing List for Internship rrogram, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Final Report, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Forms -blank, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - "Future of the Yale College Internship Program" by Tappan Wilder, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - General Information, 1987-1979 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - History of the Internship Program, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Intern Lists, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Internships offered, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Internship Surveys, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Memos to Interns, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Publicity for Fall Term Interns, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Quotations from Intern Reports, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Report of the Ad Hoc Committee on the Future of Urban Studies at Yale, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Southern Wing of Internship Program, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Supervisors of Yale College Interns, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Urban Studies: evaluations, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - Urban Studies: returned questionnaires, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - Advisory Committee, Yale College Internship Program, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Application for Internship Program, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Bursary Student, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Directors of Undergraduate Studies: correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - General Information, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - Intern Lists, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Internships: Center for the Study of Southern Culture, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Internships offered, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Interview Forms -blank, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - Miscellaneous, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - Other Universities: internship programs, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Publicity for Spring Term Interns, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - "Report on Internships in Yale College" by Antonia Stolper, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - Resumes and Transcripts of Applicants, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Advisory Committee, Yale College Internship Program, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - Future of Yale College Internship Program, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 96)
    - Intern Lists, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 97)
    - Advisory Committee, Program Yale College Internship, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 98)
    - Environmental Internships: draft proposal, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 99)
    - Environmental Internships: research for, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - Forms - blank, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 101)
    - Intern Lists, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - Publicity for Spring Interns, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - Support for Reorganization of Yale College Internship Program, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 104)
    - Future of the Program, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 105)
    - History of Yale College Internship Program, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 106)
  - Financial Records
    - Budget, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 108)
    - First National City Bank: proposed grant, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - Invoices, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 111)
    - Prospectus of Yale, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 112)
    - Campaign for Yale, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 113)
    - Internship Account, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 115)
    - Special Fees 990A-32-1987491, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 116)
    - Budget, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 118)
    - Invoices, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 120)
    - Special Fees 990A-32-1987491, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 122)
    - Budget, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 123)
    - Chart of Accounts, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 124)
    - General Ledger Numbers, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 126)
    - General Ledger Numbers: expenses, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 127)
    - General Ledger Numbers: income, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 128)
    - Invoices, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 129)
    - Special Fees 990A-32-1987491, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 130)
    - Invoices, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 133)
    - Miscellaneous, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 134)
    - Special Fees 990A-32-1987491, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - Budget, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 136)
    - Donation Account - Blue Jay Cleaners, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 137)
    - Invoices, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 138)
    - Colonial Bancorp Contribution, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 139)
    - Expense Reports, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 140)
    - Taxes, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 143)
  - Student Records
    Restricted for 75 years following date of graduation
    - Miscellaneous, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 160)
      Due to Yale policy, records are restricted until January 1, 2051
    - Non-Interns, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 216)
      Due to Yale policy, records are restricted until January 1, 2053
    - Non-Interns, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 242)
      Due to Yale policy, records are restricted until January 1, 2054
  - RESTRICTED
    - Intern Transcripts, 1976-1977 (Box 11, Folder 269)
    - Intern Transcripts, 1978-1982 (Box 11, Folder 270)
    - Recommendations for Interns, 1976-1977 (Box 11, Folder 271)
    - Recommendations for Interns, 1978-1982 (Box 11, Folder 272)
- Records of Robin W. Winks concerning the internship program, 1977-1980; Accession 1987-A-094
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2016.
  - Correspondence, memors and reports
    - 1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1980 Jan - Mar (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1980 Apr - Jul (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Intern reports, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Final report, 1979 June (Box 1, Folder 8)